喂
Hey.
停呀
Stop! Hey!
先生，停车呀！
Stop! Mister.
你叫什么名字？
What is your name?
妈的！
Shit!
What is your name？
What is your name?
意思就是你叫什么名字！
It means asking for your name.
外面有一个叫Shit的人叫我们停车！
There is a "Shit" man wanting us to stop.
这儿荒山野岭
But in such remote places,
又不知道他是什么人，怎么可以停车呢？
we should not stop for strangers.
如果我们不停车的话，我想他会被渴死！
He may die of thirst if we don't stop for him.
亚七，叫停车
Seven, tell him to pull over at once.
啊！
Yes.
师傅呀，我天天吃豆天天拉肚子
Master, I've been eating too many beans.and suffer diarrhoea from it.
再没有饭吃，我都快饿死了
If I don't have rice soon, I'll die too.
喂，停车呀，喂
Stop!
飞鸿，他哪里听得见呢？
Fai-hong, he can't hear you.
喂…你干什么？
What are you doing?
“CLIMBING”，爬！
Climbing!
停车，回头把那个人接上来！
Pal, please stop to save that guy.
这是什么话？
What kind of talk'shit?
你干什么？
What are you doing?
我从没见过这么疯的汉子！
Craziest damn thing I've ever seen.
有什么比救人一命更开心呢？
Nothing makes me happier than saving a life.
救自己一命罗！
How about saving yourself first?
小姐，实在无限感激
Much obliged Ma'am,
这里的人都叫我比利的
folks round here call me Billy!
很高兴认识你
Nice to meet you!
我是黄飞鸿
I am Wong Fai-hong!
幸会
Pleasure!
对，趁有机会，跟他多讲点英文！来
This is a good chance to.practise your English, come on.
谁？什么？那里？几时
Who, what, where, when!
几时！
When!
什么几时？
When what?
我叫十三姨
I am Diana.
幸会
Pleasure Ma'am.
几时？
When?
算了吧！
Nothing.
你会吗？
You know how?
我什么都会！
I know everything!
看，这里是美国
See, here is the America,
而这是我们身处的地方
and right there is where we are,
那边是我的家乡！
right there, that's my home town.
我和家人曾经迁往东部，但无法生活
My folks and I lived back east for a while..But things didn't work out.
所以前来寻找新生活
So we moved out here looking for a new start.
你明白我说什么吗？
You know what I mean?
YEAH
Yeah.
YEAH！YEAH！
Yeah! Yeah!
小姐
嗨
- Ma'am..- Hi
你听懂他说什么吗？
You really understand what he said?
不懂
No.
不过我会装成听懂的样子
I simply pretend that I do.
YEAH？
Yeah?
YEAH！
Yeah!
YEAH！？
Yeah!?
YEAH…
- Yeah....- Yeah...
还YEAH什么！你吃这个吧！
Cut the bull shit and start eating.
师傅，又是吃豆呀？
It's beans again?
再吃下去，我看我很难见到阿苏！
We have to be very lucky.to make it to the America.
真想不到阿苏把宝芝林开到金山来了！
Ah Sol's clinic there is also.called Po Chi Lam right?
是啊！我也没想到呀！
Exactly under the same name.
这大老远的跑到金山看他的宝芝林
Having to go through this to pay him a visit,
我就连做梦也没想到呀！
he must be joking.
师傅，不用吃豆了！
Master, we ain't no need to live on beans anymore.
你去那儿？
Where are you going?
师傅，想不想吃鸡屁股呀？
How would you like to have.chicken buff for appetizer?
咖啡，茶，还是我？
Coffee, tea, or me?
OR ME，你怎么喝吗？
Or me? How do I drink you?
你呀，一点幽默感都没有呀！
You are such a woodhead.
A , B , C , D , E , F , G , H , I , J , K…
A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, J, K, L, M, N...
你喜欢这个O吗？
Do you like O?
我喜欢！
I like an O!
以后呀，不要再说我没有幽默感了
Now, don't you ever say that.I have no sense of humour.
谢谢你
Thank you Ma'am.
我不是说过别跟陌生人讲话吗？
I've told you never talk to strangers.
来！
Come on.
小心
Be careful!
爸爸！
Daddy!
走！我们走吧！
Go, let's go.
无影腿
No-shadow Kick!
师傅，很多野人呀
Master, many barbarians here!
保护十三姨
Protect Aunt Yee.
啊
Yes!
我懂得照顾自己的
I can manage on my own.
走！
Move out.
飞鸿，阿七
Fai-hong, Seven!
马车失控啦！
The horses are beyond control.
送我一程吧！
Give me a ride!
十三姨，我来救你呀
Yee, I'm here to save you!
阿七
Seven!
这样很危险！你先坐回里面吧！
This is dangerous, go back in.
别碰我的马车啊
Hands off my carriage.
你师傅在那里？飞鸿呀？
Where is your Master? Fai-hong, where are you?
我完全听不见，小心后面
What did you say? I can't hear you..Take care of your back.
一脚！两脚！
Watch my kick!
不用你了
I don't need you.
出去
Out!
你先坐好！
Sit properly.
小心！
Be care.
飞鸿…
Fai-hong...
少筠，少筠…
Yee...
师傅
Master.
阿七
- Seven....- Seven
少筠…
Yee...
飞…
Fai...
飞鸿…
Fai-hong...
谢谢你，比利
Thank you Billy!
小姐！
Ma'am!
这是我和家人报答你的一点心意！
That's all I have to show for gratitude.from me and my family.
请笑纳
Go on take it.
承惠了
Thanks.
好货色！
It's quality!
老板，都已经洗干净了
Hi, boss, these are clean.
走吧
Let's go!
等一会儿
Just wait a moment.
嗨，露娜
Hi Lola!
阿龙，你好吗？
Hi how are you? Lone.
我很好，谢谢！
I'm fine, thank you.
啤酒
Beer.
你好，苏大夫
苏姗，你好！
- Hello, Dr. So..- Hi Susan.
你有黑眼圈哩
You've got dark circles under your eyes.
昨晚睡得不好吗？
Did you get not enough sleep last night?
我想是吧
OK! I guess.
不如我稍后到你诊所…
Well! Why don't I come over to your clinic later.
让你替我检查一下吧
So you can check me up.
好！随时欢迎你！
Sure, sure. Come by anytime!
还有…你不如跟露娜一起来吧
Yes... why don't you come along with Lola too?
这杯酒，我请客
I'll buy you a drink!
你说真的？
没问题啦！
- Are you sure?.- It's alright.
多谢
待会见
- Thank you.- See you later.
不许卖啤酒给中国人
No beer for Chinamen.
那么这杯由我来请你好了
This one's on me.
你是路过的？
You just passing through?
不！
No.
你好，镇长先生
Hello. Mr. Mayor.
给我滚！
Out!
我不过想…
I just want to...
别乱来，他可是镇长哩！
Take it easy son, he's the Mayor!
你们干吗这样？
Why are you doing this for...
滚！
Out.
走吧！对不起！
Let's go. I am sorry.
有难题吗？
Problem?
小麻烦而已
Just a little one!
记着，你不是林肯
Remember, you ain't Abraham Lincoln.
来，我请你喝一杯！
C'mon, let me buy you a drink.
心领了，林肯是不喝酒的
No, thanks Sheriff. Abraham Lincoln doesn't drink.
大惊小怪
No big deal!
镇上的啤酒不好喝呀！
The beer in town isn't good enough!
坐…坐下
Sit down...
你先给我看看嘛
没…没事了
- Let me take a look!.- It's alright.
好痛呀
坐…坐
- It hurts..- Take a seat...
等一会
Wait
他怎么了？
How's he doing?
宝芝林？那是什么意思？
Po Chi Lam? What's that mean?
做宣传嘛！
Advertisement!
苏大夫，救命呀！
Dr. So, help!
苏大夫，你在那里？苏大夫…
Dr. So, where are you?
抬进去…
Bring them in...
放在床上
Put on the bed!
苏大夫，我们在金沙河救他们回来的
We saved them from the Gold Sand River.
救起来的时候醒过一会，不久又晕过去了！
They've waken up for a short while,.then again lost consciousness.
七！
Seven!
十三姨
Aunt Yee.
阿英
师傅
- Ying,.- Yes, Master!
你帮我揉他的胸口！
Go massage his chest.
我教过你的！
By using the technique which you have just learnt.
大夫…大夫，我跟你揉这个
Doctor... may I massage this lady for you?
不，不，不，我帮她揉…
No... I'll help her...
别抢…别抢呀！抢什么抢？
Stop! What are you guys fighting for?
不要抢嘛，我们轮着做
Let's take turn.
我第一个！对对…
I'll be the first. Yes...
不…不行！她…
Wait! She is...
她是我师傅的未婚妻，怎能让你揉？
She is my master's fiancee,.don't you dare trying a finger on her.
如果你想打，吻我吧
If you want to kiss somebody, kiss me!
我并不是想吻她！
I ain't trying to kiss her.
你看这个洋鬼子，比我还要狠！
This white bastard actually wants more!
PLEASE…｜别吵！
- Please.- Shut up.
她醒啦
She's awake now.
十三姨
Aunt Yee.
肚子饿呀！
I am damn hungry.
阿七！
Seven!
飞鸿！
Fai-hong!
诞下一名男婴哩
I have a new son!
编得好漂亮，我们要好好学习
This weave is excellent,.we should learn how to do it.
爸，天神赐我一名儿子呀！
Father, the great spirit has.blessed me with another son.
这里是那儿呀？
Where am I?
停！
Stop!
你干么这样对待他？
Why do you treat him so badly?
他奇装异服的
His coat is different,
肤色与我们有别
his skin color is different,
说的语言又不一样
his speech is different.
但他流的血依然是红色的
His blood is red. Like us.
他岂会跟我们同一阵线？
But, it will not flow for us.
最后恐怕是我们会为他而流血
In the end I afraid we will be bleeding for him.
不
No!
走开
Go away.
你怎么可以对女子这么粗暴！
How can you be so rude to a lady?
你叫什么名字？…
What is your name? What is your name?
你叫什么名字？
WHAT IS YOUR NAME？
What is your name
意思是怎样用中文称呼你？
Means what's your name in Chinese!
你叫什么名字？
What is your name?
师傅，我天天吃豆我天天拉肚子
Master, I've been eating too many beans,
如果再没有饭吃，我也快将没命！
if I don't have rice soon, I'll die too.
小心！红蕃冲着我们来了！
Watch out! The Red Hair's coming.
对不起，对不起…
I beg your pardon.
黄飞鸿…黄师傅…
Wong Fai-hong. Master Wong.
十三姨
Aunt Yee.
十三姨，喝杯茶
Aunt Yee, would you like a cup of tea?
黄师傅！
Master Wong.
黄飞鸿！
Wong Fai-hong.
师傅的伞？
This is Master's umbrella!
十三姨，十三姨…
Aunt Yee...
看，是师傅的伞！
Look, this is Master's umbrella.
十三姨呀，我们吃完午餐再找吧！
Aunt Yee, shall we have lunch first?
我不饿，你们先吃吧！
I ain't hungry. You guys go ahead.
你们这些中国人到这里来干什么？
What are you Chinese doing here?
我们在找一位朋友，他在上游遇到意外
We are looking for a friend..He had an accident up river.
你该知道巴利镇长不喜欢…
Now you know Mayor Barclly...
看见中国人擅自离开应有范围
doesn't wanna see you Chinese outside your alley.
你就通融当作没见过我们吧！
Would you just pretend you did not see us?
怒难从命
Sorry. No, I can't do.
死洋鬼子！我们找人都不行呀？
You bastard, we are only searching for our friend.
他们老是把我们华人矿工不当人
They treat us Chinese miners like dogs,
我们都习惯
having all kinds of restrictions on us.
可是他们老是欺负我们
Yeah! We are always on the wrong side.
这里只有他一个人，把他干掉
Shall we stand together and overcome him now?
不不…警长对我们中国人算不错了
No... The sergeant is nice to us Chinese indeed!
你不记得嘛？
Remember?
有几次他把欺负我们的洋鬼子赶走呀！
He had driven away.some white bastards for us several times.
走呀，走呀！
Let's go!
喂
Hey!
什么
Yes?
记住，这儿绝不容许中国女人前来
Remember, no Chinese women allowed here.
此乃本地法例
That's the law.
我会记住的了
I will not forget.
“林肯”先生，后会有期
Goodbye, Mr Lincoln.
你别袒心，黄飞鸿定必吉人天相
Don't worry Ma'am. Wong Fei-hong.is gonna be just fine.
喂！你在干嘛？
Hey! What are you doing here?
再动手动脚，就对你不客气
Behave yourself or I won't give you face.
什么
What?
“WHAT”你的妈！
"What"? The hell!
“WHAT你的妈”！我喜欢呀！
What the hell? I like that.
十三姨，雨下得很大，进去吧
It's raining dogs and cats, please go back inside.
不行！我怕飞鸿回来找不到门口
No, Fai-hong won't find us when he is back.
如果你冷病了，师傅会很心痛
Master would be upset if you fell sick.
对，十三姨，进去吧
Exactly, please go back inside.
让开…
Give way...
你们看什么？
What are you guys looking at?
看女人呀
It is a woman.
女人有什么好看？
What's so excited about a woman?
汉叔，你这么老，还看？
Uncle Han, don't you think.you're too old for that?
我不能做点什么，但看看总可以吧
But I can still see well with my eyes.
走吧！走吧！今天不开门呀！
Shoot! We are closed for business today.
十三姨
Aunt Yee!
阿七，帮我试试够不够黏
Seven, help me to check its texture.
是！
Yes!
看要不要加点水？
Should I add more water?
好…
Good!... Good!...
阿苏，你在吃什么？
Sol, what are you eating?
那是浆糊！
This is glue.
黏不黏呀？
Is it sticky enough?
黏呀，黏呀
Very!
你…你又说“GOOD”！
And you! Why did you say it tastes good?
我没说，我只是点头而已
I did not! I was only nodding.
你们帮我拿些寻人启事到街上去贴
Go post these Lost and Found bills on the street.
啊！
Yes Ma'am.
你拿浆糊吧
Let's go, gluey-mouth.
这里贴一张
Post one here.
这里也贴一张
Post one here!
喂，你们在做什么？
Hey! What the hell you boys.think you're doing here?
你们为什么把我们的寻人启示撕掉？
Why did you tear our poster away?
我们在找师傅
We're looking for our master!
你们不能在这儿贴告示
You can't hang those posters here!
他到底说什么？
What did he say?
没…没什么！走吧！走吧！
Nothing... Let's go.
再贴便把你俩收监！
You hang one more poster, you're going to jail.
副队长
Deputy!
妈的！
Damn!
那些钱呀！
The money.
你身手都不错呀
Hey, you are good.
过奖过奖
Thanks partner,
你何时教我“WHAT你的妈”呀？
when are you going to teach me.some of "What your mother"?
什么？
What?
这个哩
This!
可以教我吗？
Can you show me?
你想练腿功呀？
You want to learn leg stance?
不怕辛苦就成了！
If not you can put up with the hardship.
像我这样！
Like this!
每天压腿两个时辰！
Press each of your legs like this for 4 hours.
那就成了！
That's all it takes.
好的
Alright.
小子，你们被捕了
OK boys, you're under arrest,
监狱就在那边
the jail's that way.
放心，一切已在我控制之中
Take it easy partner..I've got everything under control.
走吧
Yeah, move it.
好的，来吧
Alright come on.
请问阁下高姓大名？
What do they call you son?
我叫比利
My name is Billy!
比利，你可有兴趣做我的副手？
Billy, interested in being my deputy?
让我拿到奖金才说吧
We'll talk after I get my reward.
NICK
Nick
数完了没有？
You done yet?
真讨厌！
God damn Sheriff
给你吵一吵我又要从头再数了！
you made me lose my count..Now I have to start all over again.
警长，出手太低了吧？
Sheriff, the pay is bad.
工作又缠身
I've to cut partial of my freedom.
我明白了
I understand!
你大可在我有困难时才前来解围
You can come to work with me.only when there is a trouble.
一言为定
Sheriff, you got yourself a deputy.
那么…试试这个吧
Good, try this on for size.
如碰见到这个男人，请来诊所通知我们
Hi, if you see this man, we're at the clinic.
If you see this man, we're at the clinic.
赏面喝一杯吗？
How about a drink?
恕我失陪
No, thank you.
我要你喝
When I say drink,
你便要喝
you drink.
放开她
Hey! Leave her alone.
住口
You shut up.
再来一个
Have another.
好标致的中国娃娃啊！
You are a pretty China doll.
你走那么快干什么？
Hey lady where are you going?
你要是不喝
If you don't want to drink.
只好照头淋了
Then wear it!
不要！住手！
Stop it stop it stop it...
十三姨…十三姨
Aunt Yee! Aunt Yee.
若我是你们，便绝不这般无聊
Now all the boys,.I wouldn't do that if I were you,
你想打架，在下乐意奉陪
you wanna fight, well, you've got one.
我不是要生事
I aint looking for no fight.
太好了！
That's good.
我不服气，阿七，帮我教训他们
Now I want a fight! Seven, teach them a lesson.
好
Sure!
我们不如试点新意
Why don't we try something different, pal?
来一场友谊赛怎么样？
Care for a friendly wager?
我赌这个中国人不用枪便可把你击倒
Now I bet this Chinamen can wipe you.out without your guns.
我将赌注全押在他身上
And my money is on the Chinamen, pal
你们哪个先上？
which one is man enough to fight him?
我赢了！
I win!
不行！趁师傅不在，要打个够
No, this is only good for a warm up.since master isn't around.
阿苏，翻译
Sol, translate for me.
什么？
What?
叫他们全部一起上
Tell them to fight me all at once.
如果都能打赢我的，都算他们赢！
They are the winner if anyone of them beat me.
他说什么？
What did he say?
他叫你们一起上
He said he wants to fight you all.
如果你们赢了，钱就归你们
If you win, you can keep the money.
全都一起上？且’慢
All? Wait a minute,
我们会输的
we might lose!
阿七，他说你如…
Seven, he said if...
相信我
Trust me.
对不起！相信他才是
Sorry! Trust him!
乐死我了！
I am a happy man.
我也是！
Me too.
十三姨，你呢？
Aunt Yee, what about you?
我也一样
Me too.
谢谢！
Thank you!
我现在那有心情看风景呀
How can I enjoy this beautiful landscape now?
不如你带我去你们找到我的那个地方
Why don't you take me back to where you found me?
也许我会想起我是从那里来的
Maybe I can remember where I come from.
不过你都不知道我在讲什么
Only you have no idea on what I am saying.
衣服，你要是会说话就好了
Clothes, how I wish you could talk.
你可以告诉我，我到底是谁呀？
Then you would be able to explain everything.
师傅…金山…开宝芝林…一周年…
Master... America... Setting up Po Chi Lam....One year anniversary,
牙擦…
Sol...
这封信是我写给别人的
What's this letter about?
还是别人写给我的呢？
Is it by me or for me?
难道我叫牙擦
My name is Sol?
师傅？！我有个师傅
... and I have a master?
那我找到他，我就什么都知道了
I must find him, he will have the answer.
黄飞！
Wong Fai!
我一定认识他
I must have known him.
如果找到他我就知道我是谁了
If I found him, everything would be explained.
有何贵干？
What can I do for you?
我要娶你的女儿
I want to marry your daughter!
你岂敢侮辱我妹妹？
How dare you insult my sister?
你们是最弱的部落
You are the weakest among all the tribes,
若你拒绝将女儿嫁我，我就灭你全族
if you don't give me your daughter,.I will destory you all.
战鹰
Fierce Eagle!
我们不怕你，我们会战斗到底
We are not afraid of you,.we will fight you to death!
战鹰
Fierce Eagle!
请不要动手
Please, do not fight!
喂，不要
Hey, don't...
阿黄，别跟他打
Yellow, please do not fight him.
喂…
Hey...
来吧！
Come on!
让我试试看！
Let me try.
你想怎样？
What are you doing?
住手！
Stop it. Don't!
咦！痊愈了
I'm good, I'm good...
我真的很羡慕你们
I really envy you guys.
起码你们知道这里就是你们的家
At least you know where is your root.
我就不知道我的家在那里
I don't even know where I come from.
这儿的阳光好美
The sunshine's beautiful on this land,
但我们家乡的阳光更美
but the sunshine is more beautiful on our land.
可惜我们被迫远走他乡
But, we were forced to leave our home.
我说什么你也不知道
You don't understand a bit of what I'm saying.
也好，起码你们很幸福
That's fine, at least you are lucky.
不用像我似的
Unlike me,
整天在想，我要回到那里去！
I keep thinking where I should be heading.
我知道，我终会有日回到自己故乡
I know, someday I shall return to my land
回到自己的家
to my home.
这是感谢你为我们族人出气
For bleeding for our tribe.
谢谢
Thank you.
以后大家有什么话都不用说
From now on, verbal communication.is not necessary.
你拍我，我拍你，那不就好了吗？
Body language is much better, right?
说了忘记它，又常常想起它
I tried to forget,.but the vision keeps coming back.
真是烦
Damn it!
忘记它，忘记它
I must learn to let go.
阿黄
Yellow!
你喜欢？!
You like it?
拿去
Take it!
飞鸿！抽烟吧
Fai-hong, have a smoke!
惨啦，惨啦！十三姨脑子有问题
Oh shit! Aunt Yee is being possessed.
不是…不是脑子有问题
Nah, it is not that.
那是什么？
What's it then?
十三姨是睹物思人！
Master's stuff reminds her of him.
睹物思人？!
Master?
我都跟你说过，抽烟对身体不好
Though I did not like you to smoke,
不过，现在好不好都没有关系了
it isn't my main concern now.
他拉屎怎么去了那么久？
What is taking him so long to take a shit?
难道你想吃吗？
Are you hungry?
去你的
Take your shit.
来啊！
Come on...
我好像见过他
I think I've seen him before.
我们往别处碰运气吧
Let's go.
看！我们碰上印第安大款哩！
Hey! Look what we got here..We got some rich Indians.
我跟你讲话呀，臭红蕃！
Hey, I'm talking to you, stinking red skin.
为什么不表演一下你们的战舞？
Why don't you show me and my boys.one of your war dances?
我不会跳给白人看
I do not dance for the white man.
现在不是一样要跳吗？
You're dancing now, ain't you?
飞鸿？
Isn't he Fai-hong?
女人？
You're a woman?
你为什么跟踪我们？
Why are you following us?
我在找他呀！
I'm looking for him.
飞鸿
Fai-hong!
飞鸿？谁是飞鸿呀？
Fai-hong? Who is Fai-hong?
你呀！
You are Fai-hong!
我是飞鸿？那你是谁？
Am I? Then who are you?
我是少筠，十三姨，你的未婚妻呀
I am Yee, Aunt Yee, your fiancee!
你是我的阿姨
Since you are my aunt,
怎么又是我的未婚妻？
how can you be my fiancee as well?
阿黄
Yellow?
你叫YELLOW？
Your name is Yellow?
这里所有人都叫我YELLOW
All the people here call me Yellow.
你怎么可以随便抢人东西
You cannot just grab that!
A , B , C , D , E…
A, B, C, D, E...
都给你
Take it back!
她这么紧张这只介指
She can't do without the ring
那她为什么又不要呢？
why wouldn't she want it?
阿黄，那个女孩子似乎认识你，追她去
Yellow, that girl knows you, you must follow her.
你阴虚呀！
The darker of your inside is taking over.
我阴虚有病？
That's why I feel sick?
是呀
Absolutely.
所以就要晒着太阳来看病呀？
So I must sit under the sun more?
不，十三姨在里面，翻天覆地
Aunt Yee is making a mess in Po Chi Lam.
现在整个宝芝林的人都避开她
Everyone in Po Chi Lam.tries to stay away from her.
别以为师傅凶恶
And you thought Master had bad temper?
女人凶恶起来更可怕
You should check her out now.
好久没有见过我们的女人了
We haven't seen Chinese women for ages.
凶起来是怎么样的？
How is it when Aunt Yee gets mad?
阿苏，阿苏，阿苏
Sol...
十三姨又开锣啦
Aunt Yee is making a fuss again.
这回做什么事？
What's the fuss this time?
在收拾行李呀
She is packing up.
十三姨，你要去那呀？
Aunt Yee, where do you want to go?
回唐山
Back to China.
唐山？
什么？
- China?.- What?
准备马车，我要回唐山
Prepare a carriage for me, I am going home.
清楚没有？
Am I clear?
当然啦！
Yes, of course.
阿七，准备马车
Seven, prepare the carriage.
好！干嘛
OK. Why so?
十三姨的脑子真的有问题
Aunt Yee is having odd thinking again.
你带她到隔壁洗衣店绕一个圈
Take her for a walk around the block,
就跟她说已经到了唐山
then tell her she's already home.
好的，我知道了
OK, I get it!
十三姨，我们走
Aunt Yee, shall we?
走你的头！
What are you doing?
你们真的以为我神经病呀？
You really think I am insane?
我知道怎么样回去唐山的
I know how to get back to China.
坐十天的马车到旧金山
It takes 10 days to reach.San Francisco by carriage,
再坐半年大洋船横渡太平洋到香港
Another six months to Hong Kong by ship.
然后坐三天的火车上广州，再转车到佛山
From there it takes 3 days' on train to Canton,.then again by carriage to Fu Shan.
反正…反正我要回去呀
Whatever you say will not change my decision.
替我准备马车吧
Now will you go prepare the carriage?
好吧
Fine.
十三姨，我们走吧
Aunt Yee, we are ready now.
七！
Seven
十三姨，这边…这边
Aunt Yee, this way please...
十三姨呀，我的行李没有拿，我回去拿呀
Aunt Yee, I have forgotten my luggage,.I must go back.
阿苏，拿着，拿着
Carry it Sol.
十…十…十…三姨，十三姨！
Aunt Yee...
十三姨
十…十…十…三姨，十三姨！
Aunt Yee...
十三姨，师…师傅
Aunt Yee, it's master!
师…师…师…
Master...
十三姨，师傅…
Aunt Yee, Master...
请问？
May I ask...
我不要听你解释
I accept no explanation from you.
我不是来解释的，我想…
I ain't here to explain, I just...
我不要听你讲！
I don't want to hear anything.
你们认不认识一个叫牙擦？
You happen to know someone called Sol?
牙擦的人？
Sol?
那你们一定认识“黄飞”吧！
What about Wong Fai? Does it ring the bell?
我去问这个女人
I go ask her then.
师傅怎么这样考验我们呢？
Master is teasing us, isn't he?
不不…不是师傅…师傅…失忆！
No... Master seems to have lost his memory.
你不要过来呀，我对你不客气的
Piss off! Leave me alone, would you?
你是十三姨？
You are Aunt Yee right?
我不是
I am not!
那你认识黄飞吗？
Do you know Wong Fai then?
黄什么？
Wong... what?
我不打啦
十三姨
- Please stop!.- Aunt Yee.
不要以为你是女人，就可以乱来！
I don't give allowance just.because you're a woman.
你想干什么？
What are you doing?
我想跟你把脉
Checking your pulse.
十三姨！师傅他不是变心，是失忆呀
Aunt Yee, Master suffers from loss of memory.
失忆就可以…
So...
失忆？那怎么办呀？
He has lost his memory? What should we do?
好！让我试试他一下
Let me try.
你想干什么？
What are you doing?
我想露两手黄飞鸿的绝招，佛山无影脚
I want to show you Wong's super stance,.No Shadow Kick.
谁是黄飞鸿？
Who is Wong Fai-hong?
当然是你啦！
Sure that was you!
你就是广东十虎，民团总教头
You are one of the 1 0 Canton Tigers,.coach of the local militia.
佛山城南大街八号，专医刀伤跌打
You live in no. 8, Sing Nam Street,.Fu Shan, you're a doctor.
赠医施药，发扬国术精神
You give free treatment to the poor,.and teach Chinese Kung-fu.
长驻候教，微恶惩奸的宝芝林
You are the Master of Po Chi Lam,
第二代传人黄飞鸿！
people's hero, Wong Fai-hong.
什么是广东十虎，民团总教头？
What is 1 0 Canton Tigers? And coaching for what?
佛山城南大街八号，专医刀伤跌打
Po Chi Lam? Free treatment to people?
赠医施药，发扬国术精神
Kung-fu master?
长驻候教，做恶惩奸的宝芝林
Master of Po Chi Lam,
第二代传人黄飞鸿？!
pepole's hero Wong Fai-hong?
他就是黄飞鸿呀？!
He is Wong Fai-hong?
你没看见我们两个的姿势都是一样的吗？
Notice that we both know this post?
阿七，他根本不知道自己是谁
Seven, he forgot who he is.
你学他有什么用呢？
Showing him the post has got no use.
怎么样呀你？
Are you alright?
阿苏，你没事吗？
没事
- Are you alright, Sol?.- Yeah, I'm alright
你快点想想办法让他回复记忆呀！
You must help him regain his memory.
你！
You!
黄飞鸿！我严振东今天要跟你切磋切磋！
Wong Fai-hong, I, Yim Chun-tung,.will see how good you really are.
我严振东的铁布衫，是不会怕你打的！
Ha! With my iron cloth martial arts,.you can't beat me!
来吧！
Come on!
加厚一点，加厚一点！
Thicker! Thicker!
黄飞鸿，铁布衫是打肚子不打脸的
You should go for my stomach, not my face!
黄飞鸿，你记得纳兰元述吗？
Wong Fai-hong, do you remember Na Lan Yuan Shu?
纳兰元述呀
Na Lan Yuan Shu.
纳兰元述呀！
Na Lan Yuan Shu!
你不要再耍花样了
Quit fooling around.
七…七…
Seven!
跟我来！
Follow me!
师傅，你怎么越打越起劲呀？
Master, why are you getting fired up?
阿七，你不要再跟他打了
Seven, stop fighting with him!
阿七！
Seven!
别打了
Stop fighting!
飞鸿…
少筠！
- Fai-hong!.- Yee
少筠，你没事吧？
Yee, are you alright?
没事
I am fine.
阿七…
Seven...
我没事
I am fine!
阿七
Seven.
你怎么撞得这么厉害！
How did you fall so badly?
不是撞的
It wasn't from falling.
师傅，是你打的
Master, you hit me!
阿七，好了…
It's okay now, Seven.
师傅回来了！
The Master is back!
这次来金山，真的像发了一场春梦
This trip to America is just like a dream.
有个异国情人陪伴左右
I can do with a dream
这种春梦才不怕发
with an Indian beauty.
什么情人？
What?
那要问你才知道
Only you know the story!
我不是刚擦过了吗？
I've just cleaned my face.
介指可以送两遍！面不可以再擦一次吗？
You can give the ring twice,.but you can't wash your face twice?
可以，可以
Sure, sure.
不过你说什么我都没有什么印像！
I can't remember anything.
我也不明白你在说什么
I don't understand what you're talking about.
有没有想那个女人？
Have you thought of that woman?
没想女人！那里有空！
I don't have time to think about woman.
那有没有念她？
Do you miss her?
那就有！
Well, a little bit.
你刚才不是说没有想她吗？
You just said you haven't thought of woman.
想跟念是两件事来的
Thinking and missing are two different things.
不想又怎会念呢？
If you don't think of her, how can you miss her?
事实是这样！
But it's the truth.
事实是不想跟你讲！
The truth is I don't want to talk to you anymore.
我念着的那个，不就是你了！
But the one I miss is you.
你明知道这方面
You know I can never say,
我从来都不直接说出来的！
these things out loud.
开局啦，走快点！
The games are about to start. Hurry!
黄师傅，黄师傅
大家好，大家好
- Master Wong..- How's everyone?
师傅
- Master.- Master
师傅你找什么？
What are you looking for?
我想去那边看看！
I want to go there to have a see
黄师傅来了，龙叔！黄师傅来了！
Master Wong is here..Uncle Lone, Master Wong is here.
黄师傅来了又怎么样？
So?
黄师傅不喜欢人家赌钱的
Master Wong doesn't like people gambling.
我们先收拾，迟些时候再赌
Let's pack it up and gamble later.
不…怎么可以，我买了一
No way,
现在开一嘛，怎可以算数！
I've just won this game.
真的来了，黄师傅真的来了
Master is coming!
你赢钱了？玩多大呀？
Have you won? How much did you bet?
我也玩
不是很大
- I want in. Let's gamble together..- Just a little bit
我也来！
Come on!
师傅在干什么？
What?
黄师傅也来？
Master Wong, you too?
来！给我做座好不好？
Come, let me be the House.
来来来，来来来，大家买多点，来来来…
Come on, come on! Let's have some larger bets.
真的？
Really?
真的！多多益善，多多益善
Sure! Bet more!
买吧！黄师傅叫买，买一点点吧
Okay, if Master Wong wants us to,.we'll bet a little.
师…师…师傅…
Master...
买定离手，买定离手
Bets down and hands off.
反正大家那么多钱，又没有地方用
You've got nowhere to spend your money anyway.
全部买下去吧
Why don't you bet it all?
黄师傅，你是我们的希望
Master Wong, you are our hope,
你也这样，我们还有幻想吗？
you gamble like us, how can we find a role model?
真不习惯，黄师傅你还是做回平常的你吧
We are not used to seeing you gambling..Master Wong, why don't you be your normal self?
我们不赌了
We won't gamble anymore...
今天！
Today.
走吧！走吧！
Get out of here!
明白啦！
We understand now.
各位
People,
其实我今天来…
I thank you all,
是想感谢大家对我黄飞鸿的关心
for your concern.
我有几句话，想跟大家说
I have something to say.
大家千里迢迢
You came a long way...
漂洋过海来到这个陌生的地方…
to a foreign place,
宝芝林的开设也就是为了这一点…
Po Chi Lam was opened for this reason.
正所谓人离乡贱，物离乡贵…
When they leave home, goods are worth more.and people are worth less.
更加要知道自己是谁…
And you should know who you are.
我并不希望宝芝林生意发达…
I don't hope for good business,.that'll require you being ill.
我希望的是宝芝林可以贯彻一贯的精神…
Rather I hope Po Chi Lam.help you achieve good health,
养精蓄锐，强身健体…
build up a strong body.
取洋人之长，补国人之短…
Copy the merits of foreigners.and compensate our short-comings.
为中华民族发出百分热，耀光千分光！
And shine for the Chinese people.
其实，简单来说
Simply put,
大家记住自己是谁
you must remember who you are.
我今天就暂时说这么多，多谢大家赏面
Today, I would like to stop here,.thank you for listening.
黄师傅，你刚才说的话的确高明
Master Wong, that was a great speech.
客气…
You're too kind...
走吧，走吧
Let's go...
大叔，把钱带起来，赚点钱不容易
Sir, take the money, it was hard-earned.
黄师傅，不要再讲啦，再见，再见！
Master Wong, no more speech please.
请…请
Please excuse me...
你的金矿已经挖空了
Your gold mines dried up.
是的
Yeah.
你还有十五万的贷款我还未入账
There's still a little matter of the $1 50,000 loan,.I've discreetly left off the books.
你的口比牛屎更臭
Damn your smell like a pail of dung.
来，试试这个吧
Here, try some of these.
或者可以帮你消除口气
Maybe it'll help your breath.
还有十万元在夹万里，我自可解决一切
Put a $100,000 is in the safe..I'll take care of everything else.
什么？再要十万块？
What? Another $100,000.
照我说话做吧
Do as I say.
蒙着脸呀
Keep your faces covered,
我不想你们身分曝光
I want your identities kept secret.
我会在邮局甚至沿密西西比河岸…
I'd mark pretty face on.every post office and board...
都有我的通缉艳照！
besides the Mississippi Hell.
我想出名啊！
I want to be famous.
住口
Shut up!
不怕！去吧
I don't give a damn, let's just do it.
行啦，黄师傅不会再来啦
Let's do it, Master Wong won't come this time.
怎么了？
Why?
他没空，来吧！
He is real busy. Come on!
我做庄，买买买
I'll be the House. Bet. Bet. Bet.
发粮啦
It's pay day!
阿七呀，我在家中排行十一
Seven, I'm the 1 1th child of my family.
你叫阿七，如果我们开便利店
And I was thinking, if you and.I should open a store together,
就叫7-11好了
we'll call it 7-1 1.
汉叔，那个人干什么的？
Uncle Han, who is that guy?
他是我们领班来的，常常压诈我们！
He is our foreman, and always cheat us.
脚法快又怎么样？
So what if you can kick real fast?
别忘记这里是枪的世界
Don't forget, this is a world of guns.
怎么快也快不过子弹
You can't be as fast as a bullet.
你拿了钱吧？
Have you got the money?
我们走了
Go on and get out of here.
我想我们有…
I thought we had a...
永别
Adios.
太容易得手了！我们找点刺激好了
Hell, that's too easy,.let's find some real excitement.
枪战一定很刺激
When they start to shoot, that would be exciting.
走！走！
Get back, get out.
比利
Billy.
你干什么？
What are you doing?
你这是什么意思？
What do you mean?
你没什么吧？
Yeah, you're alright.
你没事吧？
You alright, Billy?
五十万？
Half a million dollars?
（银行被劫五十万）
"HALF A MILLION ROBBED"
我们回去小镇问镇长好了
Let's go back and pay the Mayor.and his little town a visit.
阿彼他怎么了？他好像不行了
What about Pete? He isn't gonna to make it.
阿彼，我送你一程！
Adios, Pete!
小心
Watch out!
师傅
Master.
黄师傅
Master Wong.
大家好！
你好
- How's everyone?.- How are you?
黄师傅，挂新招牌呀
Master Wong, is that a new sign?
是的
Yes.
各位！今天我有一些话要跟大家说
People, I have something to say today.
黄师傅，你又有话说呀？
Master, you have something to say again?
不用说啦！不如耍套十字拳来看看吧
Why don't you show us some fist dance.instead of a speech?
对呀！对呀！看看呀
Yeah, come on! Show us.
耍拳！耍拳吧
Show us some fist dance! Come on.
有机会，有机会
You'll get the chance!
今天是金山宝芝林成立一周年的纪念日
Today is the first anniversary.of the American Po Chi Lam.
首先我要感谢大家对我劣徒阿苏的照顾
First of all, I would like to thank you all.for taking care of my student Sol.
不要这样说！大家都是中国人
Don't mention it, we are all Chinese!
应该守望相助，互相照顾！对吗？
We should help each other, right?
各位！大家千里迢迢，飘洋过海
People, you've come a long way...
来到这一个陌生的地方
to a foreign place.
很应该要守望相助，互相照顾
You should co-operate and take care of each other.
宝芝林的开设，也是希望可以做到这一点
Po Chi Lam was opened for this reason.
但是我不希望宝芝林生意兴隆财源广进
I don't hope for good business,
因为这样代表大家病痛多多
that'll require you being ill.
我希望的是…
Instead, I hope that...
美国宝芝林是大家侨居海外的后花园
The American Po Chi Lam would.become your club house,
大家有时间坐下来喝杯茶，聊聊天耍耍拳
when you have time, you can have tea,.chat, and practise Kung-fu here.
养精蓄锐，强身健体
Build up a strong body.
我更加希望能贯彻宝芝林的一贯精神
And come in line with Po Chi Lam's spirit.
共同奋斗，取洋人之长，补国人之短
Hand in hand we copy foreigners' merits.and compensate our short-comings.
为中国人发出百点热，耀出千分光
And shine for the Chinese people.
讲完
That's all.
大家请进来，吃些点心呀
Come in! Refreshment time!
好呀！好呀！吃点心啦…
Let's go and have some snacks...
师傅呀，刚刚是不是应该先有些掌声呢？
Master, I think your speech.deserved some applause.
可能是，十三姨出来的…
Aunt Yee may come...
TIMING不是太好！
the timing of Aunt Yee's presence wasn't right.
时间
Timing.
Timing!
对！对！
Right!
大家不用客气，还有很多
Make yourself at home, there's still more...
欢迎呀各位
Welcome... Mr. Mayor,
你大驾光临令我们受宠若惊！
gentlemen, we're pretty surprised.
有什么喜庆事么？
Looks like you're having a celebration.
进去吧！
Get in there men!
我怀疑你们与银行劫案有关
I reckon you boys have something to do.with the robbery.
搜！
Search the damn place.
怎么会哩！
No! It's ridiculous!
大家不要吵
Quiet!
他说我们跟抢劫银行的事有关
They said we were involved in the robbery,
现在要搜查这里
they want to search this place.
好！清者自清
No problem, we are innocent!
大家站在一边，不要打扰捕头做事
Give way, let the police do their job.
让他搜吧！
Let them search this place.
我们找到赃款了
We've found the money!
哗，真的有呀？怎么可能发生？
What? How can it be?
看我们搜到什么！
Look what we have got here.
拘捕在场所有中国人
Arrest every last one of these Chinese,.sons of bitches!
黄师傅不要乱来呀，人命关天！
Be careful, Master, they will shoot!
走！
Move!
警长大人，我们是清白的，放我们出去呀
We're innocent, let us out!
你不可以把他们关进牢的
You can't put these people in jail.
他们根本与此案无关
They had nothing to do with the robbery.
还用你指点？
You don't tell me what I can and can't do, Billy!
别闹了，比利
Now settle down son.
案发时我跟阿七和阿苏在一起
Look, I was with Doc Sol and Seven.right before the hold-up.
他们是被诬陷的！
They've been framed.
我不管你有什么理由
I don't give a damn if you come up.with a hundred reasons.
我们在宝芝林发现赃款，证据确凿
The fact is we found some of the stolen money.in Po Chi Lam.
不是中国人抢劫，还有谁？
If the Chinamen didn't take the money, who did?
我呀？
Me?
也许是比利你
Maybe it was you Billy!
神经病！我还击中其中一个劫匪哩
No! That's crazy! I shot one of'em.
也许你想灭口！
Maybe you were trying to throw us off.
说不定你正是贼人同党
Maybe you're working with the gang.
比利，别乱来
Easy there, Billy.
别轻举妄动
I wont let you do it.
你阻止得了吗？
How are you going to stop me?
我杀了你
I'll kill you.
你没事吧？
Are you alright?
没想到他们先下手为强
I guess someone was quicker at that time.
你是中国人的真正朋友
You're a real friend to the Chinese.
比利，I 欣赏你 T00
Billy! I appreciate you too!
安静！听我说几句话
Settle down. I said settle down.
他说他帮我们争取最好的条件
He said he would get the best deal for us,
只要我们交出七个人认罪
provided that 7 of us would confess to the crime,
我们认了罪要判囚多久？
If we confess, do we go jail?
不会判囚
You can forget jail,
你们只会被问吊
they are going to hang you.
如你不认罪，所有人都要被问吊
If you don't confress to the crime,.they're going to hang you all.
记住，赃款在你们中国人的地方找到
Remember, they found the money with you Chinese.
不！不关所有中国人的事
No, not all the Chinese,
只关宝芝林的人的事嘛
only the Po Chi Lam people.
你说对不对
Am i right?
不关我们事的，黄师傅！
Master Wong, non of my business
龙叔说得对
Uncle Lone is right.
这件事的确是宝芝林的事，与其他人无关
This is Po Chi Lam's problem,.nothing to do with you all.
阿苏，你跟警长说
Sol, tell the sergeant,
我一个人担当行不行？
can I take all the responsibility?
不行！
No!
师傅，不要说你一个人担当
You can't confess to the crime alone.
就算师傅你认第一个
If you are going to be the first to confess,
我阿苏就认第二个
I'll be the second.
阿苏！
Sol!
师傅，我叫阿七
Master, my nick name is Seven,
我不是第三个，也是第七个！
if I am not the 3rd one, I will be the 7th one.
飞鸿
Fai-hong.
你们都别去，让我一个人来认
You all stay here, I'll go alone.
这次分明是冤狱
This is a set up!
黄师傅，你年青有为，一代宗师
Master Wong, you are young and capable.
应该留着宝贵的生命
Your life should be...
来帮我们华工做点事情
spared for the good of we Chinese workers.
阿汉！你不是宝芝林的人
You've nothing to do with Po Chi Lam,
不要多管闲事吧
don't get yourself into trouble!
大叔！我们不是写华工血泪史
Uncle, we are not telling others.the pathetic tales of the Chinese workers.
要写也是写华工光辉史
We want to tell the glorious history.of the Chinese workers.
我黄飞鸿就一定要站出来
I, Wong Fai-hong, should stand for all of you.
谁不同意？
Who disagrees?
来吧！
Come with me.
小姐，我去
Ma'am!
飞鸿！
Fai-hong.
都…都是我闯的祸
It's my fault!
想不到一年前来美国开宝芝林分店
I couldn't imagine that, the establishment.of Po Chi Lam in the America a year ago,
原来是为了这场浩劫铺路
would pave the way for tragedy.
还…连累了师傅你！
And I dragged Master down too...
汉叔！你怕不怕？
Uncle Han, are you afraid?
讨老婆生子，勤做工讨吃
Getting married and working hard,
在家扮皇帝，在外做奴隶
pretending as emperor at home.but working as slave outside...
这样就一辈子了
That is my life!
我们中国人的传统是死也要做只饱鬼
Sir, it is our custom,.man would die with a full stomach.
请问我可以喂饱他们么？
May I feed them?
死囚临死时会享用最后一顿饱饭
All the prisoners get their final meal.before they're executed.
也不妨吧
What can it hurt?
黄师傅
Master Wong.
我能做的…就只有这一点
This is all I can do.
黄师傅，有馅的
Master Wong, stuffed dumplings for you.
吃吧！
Eat!
师傅，靠你啦
Master, we all depend on you.
师傅，我对你有信心
Master, I have full confidence in you.
喂，再来一个呀
I want more!
还有其他人没吃
They're waiting!
为什么我们全给抓进去，你没有呢？
Why were you not in jail with us?
我没有做什么事情
I didn't do anything.
我没有…你错了！
I didn't do anything wrong.
各位市民
Citizens,
本人以镇长身分及因上帝之名
as Mayor of this town and in the name of God.
在此见证一场公平的问吊
I'm here to witness this fair.and just execution of these men.
上帝决定了他们行刑之日期
God has decided the day they are to die.
而我就决定行刑的时辰
Now I shall decide their hour.
闪开
Escape!
大家躲开呀！
Move everyone.
黄师傅，他们就是银行劫匪！
Master Wong, that's the robber.
师傅，他是打劫银行的人
Master, he was the bank robber.
我一定要抓住他，还我清白
I have to get him to clear my name.
阿苏，先去救其他人
Sol, save the others first.
师傅，这两个交给我！
Master, leave these two to me.
镇长
Mayor Barcly.
你来干什么？
What're the hell you're doing here?
我想拿取我应得的余款
I need the rest of my money.
其他中国人都怀疑我
The other Chinese is suspicious of me.
我要离开本镇
I think I should leave town.
你应该要离开本镇
You should leave town.
你想怎样？
What do you want?
我只限于跟你做交易！
I'm just doing business with you.
我要取回我们那四十万元
I want my four hundred thousand.
那是劫银行的赃款
That's the bank's money.
你讲过一切易如反掌
You told me the job was gonna a cake walk,
我有一个兄弟死了
but one of my man's been killed.
对不起，这不关我的事
Sorry, I've nothing to do with that.
这是意外
It was an accident.
我也抱歉
I'm sorry too.
妈的！
Damn it!
去死吧
Go to hell.
他妈的！
What the hell!
小子！你是怎么走过来的？
You little bastard, how did you get there?
妈的！
Shit!
他是人是鬼！
What kind of a man is he?!
给你
This is for you!
打得够劲
Plays rough!
正合我意
I like that.
够狠不够？
You like that.
算得什么？
I don't think so.
来吧！
Come on!
你在哪？
Where are you
快出来，我们谈谈吧！
Come on out now, let's talk about it
还不束手就擒？
Surrender now!
还来？
You still fight?
你是什么来的？
What the hell are you?
抓紧
Hold it tight!
放开我
Get off me
我不需要你的帮忙
I don't need your help
上来，危险！
Come on up. Look out!
我要你来证明我的清白
I need you to prove my innocence.
你简直不是人
You're not a human.
起来吧
Get up!
你怎么了？
Are you alright?
你们怎么来的？
Why are you guys here?
十三姨
Oh, Diana!
飞鸿，你没事吧？
Fai-hong, are you alright?
少筠你去那儿？
Where do you go?
我找他们来救你呀
I get them here to help you!
他们？谁是他们？
Who are they?
他们是…
不要说了
- They are....- Forget it
很多人受伤，我们先去救他们吧！
People are hurt. Let's go help them.
阿七，准备采青
Seven, get ready for lion dance.
来这里！
Come here!
恭喜你比利
Congratulations, Billy.
我相信你定会是一个好镇长
I trust you will be a good Mayor.
作为新镇长
As a new Mayor,
我以双方的友谊及了解作出声明
I proclaim in name of friendship and understanding
由今天起这儿命名为唐人街
that from this day on, this area of Fort Stockton.will be known as China Town.
我相信你一定像林肯一样，是个好领导人
I know you will be a good leader,.like Lincoln.
阿黄，保重
Farewell, Yellow.
我不是阿黄
I'm not Yellow.
我叫黄飞鸿
My name is Wong Fai-hong.
名字不重要
A name is just a name.
你永远是我们的好兄弟
You'll always be our brother.
他们是谁呀？
Who are they?
你不记得他们了？
Don't you remember them?
走吧
Come on!
各位！
Everyone...
黄师傅，不要再讲话了
Master Wong, no more speeches!
是时候上车了吧
It's time to get going.
对，你赶不上这班车，就赶不及那班船了
That's right, if you miss this train,.you'll miss the boat as well.
你们快上路吧
Now go.
是呀！是呀！
Yeah...
阿七！
Seven!
师傅，你不是准备了好多东西要讲的呀？
Master, didn't you have a long speech readied?
这么快讲完了？
How come you finish your speech so soon?
各位…
Everyone...
黄师傅，不要再说了，请吧！
Master Wong, please do go now.
上车吧
请上车吧！
- Get on the train..- Let's go!
再见了
再见
- See you!.- See you...
她到了！
Here she is!
黄师傅，你多多保重呀
Master Wong, take care.
你好吗？
How are you doing?
那个女人是谁呀？
Who is that woman?
听说是龙叔的老婆
People say she's Uncle Lone's wife.
这里是什么鬼地方？
Where the hell is it?
这么远啊
It's far from home!
好地方呀，好地方呀！
It's a nice place. It's a nice place!
对呀！
Right!
我很累呀
I am tired!
起码要休息三天才可以侍候你们！
I'll need at least 3 days' rest.before I can take care of you.
没问题，三天就三天啦
No problem. As you wish.
那为什么他们这样开心的？
Why are they so happy?
开心！
Happy!
我每天不能超过十个人，初一十五要吃素
No more than 10 people per day,.and I break on the 1st and 15th.
你真的不记得那个印第安女人呀？
You really don't remember the Indian woman?
一点印象都没有呀
No, I remember nothing!
再见了！
See you!
师傅，十三姨，再见了！
Master, Yee, See you
阿苏，不用送了，回去招呼铺子吧！
No need to see me off, Sol, go tend to the store.
明年去探你们吧！再见了！
See you next year!